欢迎收看《造物小百科》
Today on how it's made.
全息照片，面向未来的投影技术
Holograms, projections for the future.
包装印刷，属于大众的安迪·沃霍尔
Package printing, Andy Warhol for the masses.
安迪·沃霍尔，波普艺术代表画家
皮肤培植，重度烧伤者的希望
Skin culture, hope for those who suffered severe burns.
还有罐装甜玉米，从玉米棒到罐头只需几把快刀
And canned sweetcorn, from top to can via a few sharp knives.
但首先，全息照片不只是美丽迷人
But first, holograms aren't just beautiful and fascinating.
它们自带一种高科技的神秘感
They have a certain high-tech mystique about them.
那么，是时候揭开谜底了
Well, it's high time we reveal the mystery.
全息照片其实就是图像的层叠变化
Holograms are simply layered variations of an image,
每一层都以不同的方式反射光线
each one causing light to reflect in a different way.
全息照片是一种由两束激光的干涉产生的三维照片
A hologram is a three-dimensional photograph produced by the interference of two laser beams.
光线的颜色随波长不同而变化
The colour of light rays varies according to the wavelength.
快门开启时，要么挡住光线，要么让光线通过
A shutter, when activated, either blocks or lets the light ray pass through.
这里，光束以90度角一分为二
Here, the beam is split in two at a 90° angle.
屏幕上清晰可见两束光的干涉
The interference of the two beams is clearly visible on the screen.
干涉条纹非常清晰分明
It has highly defined fringes.
光束需要保持稳定
The beams need stability
因为投射在屏幕上的干涉图案对微小振动极其敏感
because the pattern of interference projected on the screen is extremely sensitive to minute vibrations.
轻轻敲一下桌子就可能毁掉它
A light tap on the table can easily spoil it.
团队将用这个黏土雕塑制作全息照片
The team will create a hologram from this sculpture made of modelling clay.
雕塑用磁性底座固定，确保纹丝不动
The sculpture is positioned with a magnetic base for tremor-free support.
随后在物体前方放置一块玻璃
They then place a glass in front of the object.
这里就是光束经过的准确位置
Here's the exact point where the light beam passes.
为达到绝对稳定，工作台是一块2吨重的钢板，由18个气垫支撑
To achieve absolute stability, the table is a 2-ton block of steel which rests on 18 air tubes.
分束器将光束一分为二
A beam splitter separates the beam in two,
一束射向物体后方，另一束射向前方
directing one behind the object and the other in front of it.
其中一束光射向雕塑前方
One part of the beam heads toward the front of the sculpture.
光束先经过物镜，使光线扩散
The beam first passes through an objective lens, which diffuses the light.
然后被抛物面镜反射
Then it's reflected by a parabolic mirror,
以免光强损失过多
which prevents it from losing too much of its intensity.
和摄影一样，这里也需要胶片
As in photography, film is required.
全息胶片附着在一块玻璃板上
This holographic film is attached to a glass plate.
再盖上一块玻璃板，把胶片固定住
Then another glass plate is added so that the film is secure.
任何大于激光波长1/10的位移都会毁掉图像
Any movement greater than 1/10 of the laser's wavelength will spoil the image.
现在打开激光器
The laser is now turned on.
光强达到约250毫瓦
The intensity of light ray reaches about 250 milliwatts.
模型正常曝光时间约为1秒
The normal exposure time of the model to the beam is about 1 second.
但用脉冲激光制作的全息照片，曝光时间极短
But some holograms made with a pulsed laser are exposed
仅有12纳秒，比普通曝光短得多
to the light for 12 nanoseconds, an infinitely shorter period of time.
和摄影一样，胶片需要显影
As in photography, the film has to be developed.
这些盘子里装着化学溶液，称为显影液
These trays contain chemical solutions, called developer.
首先，胶片在显影液中浸泡2分钟
First, the film is soaked in the developer for 2 minutes.
这种溶液会使感光的银盐变黑
This solution blackens the silver salts, which have reacted to the light.
随后胶片浸泡在漂白液中，彻底清除变黑的银盐
Then the film is soaked in a solution called bleach to completely eliminate the silver salts which blackened it.
现在冲洗胶片
Now the film is rinsed.
这一步用于去除感光乳剂中的酸性物质，以免污染下一道溶液
This step is used to eliminate the acids in the emulsion, so as not to contaminate the next solution.
胶片慢慢变得透明
The film slowly becomes transparent.
然后用清水冲洗
It's then rinsed in clear water.
再在润湿剂中浸泡1分钟
And it's soaked for 1 minute in a wetting agent,
以消除所有水渍
which eliminates all water spots.
随后胶片干燥，显现它的奥秘
The film is then dried to reveal its secrets.
这就是从雕塑制作出的全息成品
And here's the finished hologram, created from the sculpture.
有些全息照片可以动起来，由一系列静态全息图生成
Some holograms can be animated, which are generated from a series of still holograms.
根据项目的复杂程度
Depending on the complexity of the project,
制作一张全息照片需要1到5小时
a hologram can be produced in between 1 and 5 hours.
懂得原理后，其实很简单
Simple once you know how.
普通的产品包装上塞满了各种信息
Your average product packaging is crammed with so much information
很难看出藏在说明和配料背后的艺术
it's hard to see the artistry behind the instructions and ingredients.
制作包装需要投入大量心思
An incredible amount of thought goes into making packaging
让包装独一无二、过目难忘，并吸引消费者
that's unique, instantly recognisable, and attractive to the consumer.
所有消费品都或多或少有包装
All consumer products are packaged in one way or another.
制作从烧蚀铝版开始
Fabrication starts with the burning of an aluminium plate.
铝版装到滚筒上，用激光开始烧蚀
The plate is placed onto a cylinder, and using a laser, the burning begins.
图像6分钟即可显现
The image appears in 6 minutes.
这块印版将用来在包装上压印图案
This plate will make the printing impressions on packages.
激光必须校准得十分精确
The laser has to be perfectly calibrated.
用这块测试印版
Using this test plate,
印刷从手工调配油墨开始
printing starts with the hand mixing of inks.
如果没有现成想要的颜色
If the desired colour does not exist,
就要用各种其他颜色调配出来
it has to be made up from a mix of various other colours.
用刮刀进行油墨试印
An ink trial is done with a spatula,
再用手动小压机进行颜色测试
and using this small manual press, colour ink tests are done.
油墨涂在纸上，与原稿颜色对比
The ink is spread onto paper, and the colour compared to the master design.
如果颜色一致，就可以开动印刷机
If they do match, the presses can be started up.
这是六色胶印印刷机
This is a six colour offset process printing press.
印刷机通过吸附和摩擦供纸，每小时吞吐8000张
The press is fed by a suction and friction process, devouring 8,000 sheets an hour.
现在把印版装到印刷机滚筒上
Now the printing plate is placed onto the press cylinder.
这块印版将接触到着墨辊
This plate will come into contact with the inking rollers,
这些辊筒从墨斗中取墨
which feed off the ink reservoir.
为防止油墨干燥，振荡器会维持油墨粘度
To prevent it from drying, ink viscosity is maintained with an oscillator.
印刷机启动，单小时产量达8000印
The press starts up and reaches a production rate of 8,000 impressions in a single hour.
印刷机由多个独立颜色印刷单元组成
The press is comprised of individual colour printing units.
纸张依次通过各个单元
The paper sheet passes from one unit to the other.
每一步都印上一种新颜色
Receiving a new colour at each step.
最终质检确保颜色和位置准确无误
A final quality check guarantees that the colours and position is correct.
最后一步是纸盒的折叠与粘合
The final step is the folding and gluing of the boxes.
这块压痕板在纸板上压出折痕
This grooved plate makes folding marks on the carton.
这台机器完成切割、压痕以及除废，每小时处理6000张
And this machine does the cutting, the embossing, and stripping of the sheets at a rate of 6,000 an hour.
模切刀切开纸板
The cutting die slices the carton sheets and,
配合压痕板形成折边
together with the grooved plate, makes the folding joints.
这块垫板滑入模切刀后方，使切割受力均匀
This sheet is slid behind the cutting die to equalise the cutting of the sheets.
这堆积如山的3000张纸板即将开始切割
This enormous pile of 3,000 sheets is now ready to be cut.
压痕机的进料装置每小时处理6000到8000张
The embossing press feeder handles between 6 and 8,000 sheets an hour.
辊轮引导纸板进入压痕机
Rollers guide the sheets in the direction of the press,
纸板在这里被机器压出痕迹
and here the sheets are embossed by the machine.
随后检验压痕的精度
The precision of the embossing is then verified.
接下来是纸板的模切
Next comes the cutting of the sheets.
模切单元剥离去除多余部分
The cutting unit strips and removes the unnecessary
纸板碎片被吸走，最终送去回收
pieces, and the carton scraps are sucked up for eventual recycling.
边角料也可以用手锤敲掉
The scraps can also be cut away manually using a hammer,
纸板端头料送去回收
and the carton end pieces are sent off for recycling.
剩下的就是纸盒组装
All that remains is the assembly of the packages.
高速粘合机每小时能生产3万到4万个纸盒
With a high-speed gluing unit that can construct 30,000 to 40,000 boxes per hour,
粘合从沿折痕折叠纸板开始
gluing begins with the folding of the sheets, following the folding marks.
成型的纸盒侧面随后粘合在一起
The sides of the formed box are then glued together.
制作一个包装盒平均需要5到8道工序
An average of between 5 to 8 steps are needed to fabricate a packaging box.
这家工厂每天生产100万到200万个纸盒
Every day, this plant produces between 1 and 2 million boxes,
每年需要近4000吨纸板
requiring almost 4,000 tons of cardboard every year.
接下来是《造物小百科》：皮肤培植
Coming up in how it's made: skin cultures,
皮肤移植可以决定生死
skin grafts can mean the difference between life and death,
为重度烧伤者带来希望
offering hope for those who've suffered severe burns.
还有罐装甜玉米
And canned sweet corn.
对工程壮举感兴趣的人都会欣赏从玉米棒到罐头的旋风之旅
Anyone with an appetite for feats of engineering will appreciate the whirlwind journey from cob to can.
广告之后见
See you after the break.
欢迎回到《造物小百科》
Welcome back to how it's made.
稍后我们将介绍罐装甜玉米
Later we look at canned sweet corn,
一场从玉米棒到罐头的旋风工程
a feat of whirlwind engineering from cob to can.
但首先，来看看重度烧伤患者
But first, for people who've suffered severe burns.
他们不是绝望的
There's hope.
可以用皮肤移植治疗
They can be treated with skin grafts,
移植实验室培育的人类皮肤
using human skin that's been cultured in a lab.
接受移植的患者，往往疤痕更少，愈合时间也短得多
Patients who receive these grafts tend to develop less scarring and usually heal in a fraction of the time.
要培植皮肤，必须先分离、收集皮肤细胞并让其增殖
To grow skin, skin cells have to be isolated and collected and made to multiply.
一切始于取一小块皮肤样本
It all begins with the removal of a small skin sample.
这块样本中的1000万个细胞足以培养一份皮肤
The 10 million cells in this piece are enough to make a culture.
皮肤浸泡其中
The skin soaks in.
培养基中含有青霉素和庆大霉素
A medium containing penicillin and gentamycin,
这两种抗生素可防止细菌感染
antibiotics which protect it from bacterial infection.
现在取一小块皮肤，在培养皿上用手术刀精细切分
Now a piece of skin is cut and delicately sectioned on a petri dish with a scalpel.
小心地把脂肪与真皮分离
The fat is gently detached from the dermis,
因为培养用不到脂肪
since it will not be needed in the culturing.
皮肤切成细条，因为嗜热菌蛋白酶
The skin is cut into thin strips, because thermolysin,
这种分离真皮与表皮的酶，在小面积上作用更高效
the enzyme which separates the dermis from the epidermis, acts more efficiently on small surfaces.
随后一种酶破坏真皮与表皮细胞之间的联系
Then an enzyme destroys the links uniting the dermis and epidermis cells.
该过程在37摄氏度培养箱中培养3小时
This procedure is carried out in this incubator over three hours at a temperature of 37 degrees centigrade.
培养结束后，取出培养皿离开培养箱
Once incubation is over, the petri dish is removed from the incubator.
只保留表皮细胞，即角质形成细胞
Only the epidermis cells, called keratinocytes, are retained.
表皮与真皮被精确地分离开
The epidermis is detached from the dermis with great precision.
现在把皮肤条放入胰蛋白酶处理单元
Now the strips are placed in a trypsination unit.
一种酶会破坏表皮细胞间的连接，以便分离它们
An enzyme will destroy the links uniting the epidermis cells in order to isolate them.
这一操作促使细胞增殖
This operation signals the cells to multiply.
为了提高胰蛋白酶的效力，处理单元被放在振荡器上
In order to increase the effectiveness of trypsin, the trypsination unit is placed on an agitator.
胰蛋白酶：分解蛋白质的酶
含细胞的悬浮液被抽出
The liquid containing the cells in suspension is drawn off.
现在需要对液体进行分离
Now the liquid must be separated.
所需的细胞位于试管底部，而上方的含胰蛋白酶上清液需要去除
The desired cells lie at the bottom of the tube, while the upper floating solution containing the trypsin has to be removed.
用真空系统抽走胰蛋白酶溶液
The trypsin solution is drawn off with a vacuum system.
为了清除所有胰蛋白酶残留
In order to eliminate all traces of trypsin,
加入更多化学试剂，让混合物重新悬浮
further chemicals are added and the mixture put back into suspension.
现在，小样本中的细胞需先计数，再进行第二次离心
Now the cells from the small skin sample have to be counted before being centrifuged a second time.
细胞在显微镜下人工计数
The cells are counted by hand using a microscope.
或用这种专用设备
or in this specialist equipment.
确定活组织检查所得细胞的确切数量
The exact number of cells obtained during a biopsy is determined
并筛选最适合生长的皮肤细胞
as well as the best skin cells needed for maximum growth.
角质形成细胞被分装到装有培养基的培养瓶中
The bottom portion of keratinocytes is divided in these flasks containing a culture medium,
其成分与血液相似
whose composition resembles blood.
放入37摄氏度的培养箱，细胞将在瓶中增殖一周
Placed in an oven at 37 degrees, the cells will multiply over a week in these flasks.
浸泡细胞的溶液每2天更换一次
The solution in which the cells are immersed is changed every 2 days.
不到一周，细胞几乎铺满整个培养瓶表面
In less than a week, the cells have almost covered the entire surface of the flask.
现在可以再次用胰蛋白酶处理，扩增出50个新培养瓶
They can now be trypsinated anew to create a further 50 flasks.
这些新瓶再放入培养箱约一周
Which in turn will be placed in the oven for about 1 week.
皮肤片铺满培养瓶内壁
Skin strips carpet the inner surface of the flask.
然后用刮刀将其剥离
They are then detached with a spatula.
用类似烙铁的加热装置把培养瓶一分为二
The flasks are cut in two with a heating unit resembling a soldering iron.
为便于操作，在厚度不足0.1毫米的皮肤片上盖上纱布
To make handling easier, gauze is placed on the skin strips whose thickness is less than one tenth of a millimeter.
移植物最终覆盖在伤口上
The graft is then finally placed on the wound.
10天后取下夹子和纱布
Clamps and the gauze will be removed after 10 days,
患者开始愈合
and the patient begins the healing process.
说到蔬菜，没有比新鲜玉米棒更好的了
When it comes to vegetables, there's nothing like fresh corn on the cob.
但正如任何学生所说，罐装甜玉米才是大学食堂的主料
But as any student will tell you, canned sweet corn is the staple ingredient in any university kitchen.
任何对工程壮举有胃口的人
And anyone with an appetite for feats of engineering
都会欣赏从玉米棒到罐头的旋风之旅
will appreciate the whirlwind journey from cob to can.
纵观历史，食物的保存方式包括烟熏、冷冻、风干和腌制
Throughout history, food. Preserving has included smoking, freezing, drying, and salting.
19世纪初，尼古拉·阿佩尔建厂
In the early 19th century, Nicolas Appert built a factory
阿佩尔：罐头保藏法发明者
用密封玻璃罐保存食物
to preserve foods in hermetically sealed glass jars,
并煮沸杀菌
and to sterilise them by boiling.
但玻璃易碎，于是在1810年
But glass was breakable, and so in 1810,
一位名叫杜兰德的英国人发明了马口铁罐头
an Englishman named Durand invented the tin can,
最初在美国独立战争中为军方使用
first used by the military in the American War of Independence.
用于罐装的玉米在8月中旬到10月中旬之间收获
Corn destined for canning is harvested from mid August to mid October.
从收获到罐装间隔不到4小时
Less than 4 hours pass between harvesting and canning procedures,
以尽可能保留成品的营养价值
so as to conserve much of the nutritional value of the product to be sold.
卸下卡车上的玉米就开始了整个流程
The unloading of the trucks starts the process
这里每年要罐装13.6万吨玉米
that annually consumes the 136,000 tons of corn that is canned here.
玉米棒通过传送带运入工厂
The cobs are transported into the plant on a conveyor,
首先经过去粒机
and will first pass through a kernel remover.
这台设备装有多个反向旋转的滚筒
A unit equipped with several counter-rotating cylinders,
去除包裹着玉米棒叶子和须
removes the leaves and silk which surround the cob.
短短几秒内，玉米棒外层就被完全剥离
Within only a few seconds, the cob is completely stripped of its covering.
在这里排好队，等待去粒机处理
Here they are lined up, ready to be handled by the kernel remover.
玉米棒穿过机器时被脱粒
The kernels are removed from the cobs by going through the machine,
刀片在眨眼间切下玉米粒
where knives remove the kernels in a fraction of a second.
每台设备每小时能对1.5吨玉米脱粒处理
Each of these units remove 1.5 tons of kernels every hour.
每天停机2次，检查、清洁并磨快刀片
Twice a day, the machines are stopped to inspect, clean and sharpen the blades.
玉米粒落向中间
The corn kernels fall into the middle,
玉米棒从旁边丢下
while the cobs themselves are moved to the sides.
玉米粒进入这台旋转滚筒
The kernels are entered into this rotating drum,
去除比玉米粒大的杂质
which removes any particles larger than the kernels.
这一过程中没有任何浪费
Nothing is wasted in this processing.
玉米渣、叶子和玉米棒之后用作动物饲料
Corn residues, leaves, and cobs will be used later as animal feed.
玉米粒落入由水和切粒时榨出的玉米汁组成的混合液
Now, the kernels fall into a mix composed of water and the juice obtained when cutting the corn kernels themselves.
这种液体混合液可以输送玉米粒而不损伤它们
The liquid mix allows for the transporting of the kernels without damaging them.
烫漂在这台巨大的滚筒中进行
Blanching is carried out in this huge cylinder.
烫漂：热水短时加热以灭酶护色
螺旋输送器把烫漂过的玉米粒送到表面
A worm screw brings the blanched kernels to the surface,
在这里进行目视检查，检验玉米粒的质量
where a visual inspection verifies the quality of the kernels.
剩下的就是装入罐头
All that remains is to pack them into these cans.
成千上万的罐头被送往装罐车间
Thousands of cans are carried to the filling department.
装罐由这台旋转式灌装机完成
Filling the cans is done from this rotating filling machine,
每分钟最多可灌装450罐
and can handle up to 450 cans a minute.
落到一旁的玉米粒
The kernels, which fall to the side,
稍后会被收集起来，送回灌装线
are gathered up later and returned to the filling line.
这里加入由水、盐和糖配成的盐水
Here, a brine composed of water, salt, and sugar is added.
盖子被牢牢盖在罐子上
Lids are securely attached onto the containers.
但罐装还没结束
But the canning is not yet finished,
因为重要的质检还没开始
as important tests have to be carried out.
实验室检测确保产品质量
Laboratory tests assure the quality of the product.
首先检测罐头的密封性
First, the watertight properties of the cans,
再检查灌装重量和玉米粒品质
then the filling weight, and the quality of the kernels are checked.
与此同时，罐头继续在工厂中行进
In the meantime, cans continue their way through the plant,
还有最后一步：杀菌
and one step remains: sterilisation.
杀菌在这台炉子中进行，温度120摄氏度，最长持续6分钟
Sterilisation takes place in this oven at 120 degrees centigrade and lasts up to 6 minutes.
这是关键一步，确保产品保质期长达18个月
This is a crucial step, because it guarantees that the product is reliable and that it will remain so for 18 months.
最后进行口味抽样，确认甜玉米符合质量标准
Lastly, taste samples are carried out to determine that the sweet corn hits quality standards.
在这座庞大的工厂里
In this giant facility
每年能生产出惊人的4300万罐玉米
an amazing total of 43 million cans of corn are produced every year.
一个囊中羞涩学生的美食梦想
A cash-strapped student's culinary dream.